Nathan Davenport

PERSONAL STATEMENT

Relocating from Atlanta, Georgia, to the New York City area, also open to remote options. US Citizen developer with three years of post-college experience in the software industry. Experience with both frontend and backend technologies, payment systems and physical hardware, Kubernetes based SaaS products, and user experience design. Skilled at adapting to new teams and workloads, getting along with new people and environments, and being an overall flexible engineer.

E-Mail: nathandaven@gmail.com, LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/nathandaven, Personal Website: nathandaven.com

EDUCATION

Georgia Institute of Technology

Atlanta, Georgia, Graduated May 2022

Bachelor of Science in Computational Media with Highest Honors, Concentrations in Media (CS) and Interaction Design (UI/UX), Recipient of Dean's List Award and Zell Miller Scholarship. Computational Media is a joint Computer Science degree with the Ivan Allen College of Liberal Arts.

RELEVANT EMPLOYMENT

NCR Voyix – Software Engineer II

Atlanta, Georgia, Oct. 2023 - Present

- Experienced a company split, was promoted to a Level II engineer, and joined a new team while also gaining many more responsibilities within the self-checkout project and organization.
- Worked with an international team across several time zones, became more familiar with the QA process, and became the person of contact for both my former duties and specializing in a new application after a massive refactor and cleanup of an existing service.
- Used Typescript technologies to work on several applications using the Observer pattern enabled by frameworks such as RxJS and Nest JS, and also became a code owner of one of these projects, as well as REST endpoints and Jest unit testing.
- Diagnosed hard to understand bugs and worked with QA teams across the globe to improve the product and company metrics.

NCR Corporation – Software Engineer I

Atlanta, Georgia, June 2022 - Oct. 2023

- Worked on the automation team for a self-checkout product and became accustomed to a rapidly paced work environment through
 exposure to massive codebases and architectures, in-depth Kubernetes and Docker experience, and rapid Typescript and Node
 development.
- Became proficient at working with CI/CD pipelines, testing libraries, automation pipelines, E2E and user testing, physical hardware
 interactions, and much more.
- Used technologies such as Cypress, Cucumber, Typescript, GitHub Actions, and Jenkins to improve company metrics and increase product quality.
- Rapidly became familiar with Agile development, Jira, constant meetings and time management, sprints, scoping, and eventually became a main point of contact for automation on the project, as well as a designated code owner for all testing scripts.

Georgia Institute of Technology – CS 2261 Teaching Assistant At

Atlanta, Georgia, Aug. 2021 - May 2022

- Worked under Professor Aaron Hansen to teach C using Gameboy Advance hardware, after being selected to TA for several semesters after earning one of the highest scores on the final project, a Zelda inspired RPG.
- Developed a deep understanding of the C programming language on a hardware level and how to interact with GBA hardware, including code structure, processor functions, pointers, memory management, DMA, and much more.
- Lead recitation courses on certain topics, creating demo and instructional material, and providing demo code for students
- Worked long rewarding hours of grading homework, projects, and tests, as well as several hours of office hour time each week for student help.

Government Window, LLC. - Software Engineering Intern

Kennesaw, GA Jan. 2021 - Aug. 2021

- Created new printed branding materials for the company, and redesigned and managed the hiring process to create a new company website at governmentwindow.com.
- Worked to create features for the payment software back end using PHP, JavaScript, and HTML/CSS, and working with the company's large MySQL database. Improved SEO in the process.
- Created dozens of new static websites for various counties around Georgia using modern web technologies.
- Updated the entire payment front-end for the company's payment software based on my Figma designs and added features to the PHP back end to support the new software design.

SKILLS

Languages - Typescript, Javascript, Java, Python, C#, C/C++, Bash, GitHub Actions

 $\textbf{\textit{Technologies}} - \text{Kubernetes}, \text{Docker}, \text{PostgresSQL}, \text{Cypress}, \text{Node.JS}, \text{RxJS}, \text{Nest.JS}, \text{React.JS}, \text{Looker}, \text{MQTT}, \text{CI/CD pipelines}, \text{REST}, \text{Colored pipelines}, \text{Co$

Software - Google Cloud Platform, Jira, Confluence, VS Code, IntelliJ, Figma, Adobe Software, Microsoft Office

General Skills – Excellent Verbal Communication, Responsive, Consistent, Problem Solving, Writing and Grammar, Layout and Design, Research and Education, Agile and Scrum concepts, Photo Editing, Video Editing, Graphic Design, Web / Cloud Development, Front End Development, Back End Development